Charan Kumar Thogata

Software Engineer Test

charan.kumart1996@gmail.com \$618931020

● Bengaluru, India

▼ Portfolio

Profile

Dedicated and professional software tester with 1 year of IT experiences working in quality assurance and general software development. Excellent analysis, evaluation, and perception abilities, as well as strong attention to small details for accurately identifying all problems and bugs quickly and effectively. Prioritize communication to collaborate with other testers and designers and describe bugs to be eliminated.

Professional Experience

04/2022 - present Bengaluru, India

Software Engineer Test

Zeliot Connected Services ☑

- Having 1+ years of IT experience as a Software Test Engineer both in Manual and Automation(Selenium/Playwright java).
- Worked on Enterprise IoT Solutions with AgileMethodology
- Well-Acquainted in Software Development Life cycle(SDLC) and Software Testing Life cycle(STLC).
- Experience in writing Test Scenarios and Test Cases based on Test case design Techniques.
- Thorough hands-on experience with all levels of testing including Smoke, Functional, Re-testing, Regression, and Sanity.
- Experienced in automating web applications using Selenium WebDriver, Playwright using Java and Maven
- Proven skills in handling elements in selenium WebDriver, writing and executing automation Scripts in Java for a highly transactional web application.
- Worked in Automation frameworks like POM Driven Framework, TestNGFramework,
- Data-driven Framework, Hybrid Framework, and good knowledge of Cucumber framework.
- Expertise in creating Extent Report and Executing the script with testing.xml
- Experiences in running automation scripts using Jenkins and running using a cron job, After executing sending reports via mail using mail REST API.
- Automated socket connection code is used to work simulation for our portal and runs in cron daily on a Linux server.
- Worked on Mobile Application Testing using Android apk
- Worked on Load Testing using the Jmeter tool
- · Good knowledge of scrum, and Agile methodology, Worked with bug-tracking tools like Jira
- Guided new team members to get acquired project knowledge and processes
- Experienced in handling Clients and understanding projects.

10/2020 - 12/2020 Bangalore, India

Senior Assistant Help Desk Technician

EIT SERVICES INDIA PRIVATE LIMITED

- Troubleshooting of VPN issues, MS office, Basic computer issues
- Assigning new roles and going required access on AD
- working on ticketing tools to resolve the issues.

Projects Handled

TrakZeus 🖸

Roles and responsibilities:

- Understanding the application thoroughly with the help of the required Documents.
- Preparation of Functional Test Cases and Test Data, Executed Functional and Regression Test cases
- Responsible for running test cases and posting defects, Preparing Defect Reports, and Tracking the same
- Involved in Security Vulnerability testing using OWASP ZAP Automation
- · Assisted in grooming new team members by providing KT

Aquilatrack 🛮

Roles and responsibilities:

- Understanding the application thoroughly with the help of the required Documents.
- Preparation of Functional Test Cases, Test Data, and Executed Functional and Regression Test cases
- Responsible for running test cases and posting defects and Preparing Defect Reports and Tracking the same

Skills			
JAVA	• • • •	Selenium	••••
Playwright	• • • • •	Eclipse	• • • • •
VS Code	• • • • •	MAVEN	• • • • •
TestNG	• • • •	Cucumber	• • • • •
Jmeter	• • • • •	GitLab	• • • • •
GitHub	• • • • •	Linux	• • • • •

Education

08/2016 – 10/2020 Bengaluru, India **B.Tech in Mechanical Engineering**

engaluru, India REVA University ♂

Certificates

 JAVA, Manual Testing, Automation Testing

Publications

Investigation of Mechanical Properties and Wear Behavior of Al 2024 Matrix Reinforced with Si3N4 and Graphene $\ \ \, \Box$

IJSER

Declaration

I hereby declare the above-listed particulars of information and evidence are true to the best of my knowledge.